Ahmad!
How are you doing?
你好嘛？
What's up, Rafi?
你好嗎 Rafi？
How have you been? How's your health?
你過的如何？ 健康狀況呢？
I brought you some hot coals.
我帶了一些燙煤炭給你
Where have you been all week?
你這禮拜都在幹嘛阿？
Sakhi saw me stealing from his shop,
Sakhi 看到我在他的店裡偷東西，
so I had to hide out for a while.
所以我躲了一陣子
How's work?
工作如何？
Not bad.
還不錯。
But I have to get back, my father's waiting.
但我爸在等我回家了
Let's hang out today.
我們出去玩嘛～
There's no way my dad will let me.
我爸不可能答應的
Oh, come on, take the day off.
唉唷～休息一天嘛～～
Rafi! What are you doing?
Rafi!你在幹什麼？
I was getting water.
我只是在裝水
Get back to the shop.
回到店里來
I'll see you later.
等一下見了
Get out of here, bastard.
離開這裡！小混蛋
Let me bless you!
讓我為你祈福！
My smoke cures the evil eye!
我的煙能治癒邪惡的眼！
Quick! Get out your money!
快！掏出你的錢來！
May you become a mullah!
願你成為一位穆拉！
May you own three Corollas!
祝福你擁有三位新娘！
Mister, a blessing!
先生！要祝福嗎？
Uncle, let me bless you. Come on.
叔叔，讓我祝福你吧，拜託嘛。
Just 5 or 10 rupees!
只要5或10盧比！
Come on, uncle!
好嘛，叔叔！
What about you? Just one blessing!
那你呢？就一次祝福！
I will pray that you get a better car!
我會祝福你得到更好的車子！
Father, can I get some time off this afternoon?
爸爸，我今天下午可以有點時間休息嗎？
Eat your food. We have work to do.
吃你的飯，我們還有工作要做
I'm full.
我吃飽了
Clean up these plates, then.
那就把盤子洗一洗吧
Rafi, my son.
Rafi, 我兒阿
Yes?
是的？
You have two hours.
你有兩個小時。
I was about to leave without you.
我差點要離開你了
You wouldn't have done that.
你才不會那樣做呢
All the best buzkashi riders will be competing.
所有最棒的[馬背叼羊]好手都會去參加
You're going to love it.
你會愛上這個活動的
Come on, hurry!
來阿！快點！
All aboard! Last stop, Sar-e-Kotal!
啟程出發！往Sar-e-Kotal!
Look over there.
看那邊！！
He's got the goat!
他拿到羊了！！
A buzkashi rider grabs the goat,
一位[馬背叼羊]選手抓住羊，
then they fight over it all the way to the flag.
然後其他人要搶到，拿到旗子那邊
Once the rider goes around the flag,
只要選手接近旗子附近了，
he takes the goat back to the circle.
要把羊拿進那一圈裡面
That's how you score a point.
這樣你就會得一分
He's got it! He's got it!
他得到了！他得到了！
Go! Go!
快去！快阿！
Look! He's bringing it back to the circle!
你看！他要把羊帶回圈圈裡了！
Go! Go!
快去！快去！
Come on!
快阿！
He made it!
他成功了！
Attention all spectators!
請注意! 各位觀眾
They are as fast as deer, as focused as tigers ..
他們如鹿般快速，如虎般專注...
.. as quick as jackrabbits, and as fit as foxes!
...如野兔般矯健，如狐狸般敏捷！
All buzkashi riders in Afghanistan ..
所有在阿富汗的[馬背叼羊]好手們！
.. from the North, from the South, from the West!
從北方、南方、西方來！
Cheer for these champions!
為冠軍們歡呼！！
Look at that. I got one!
看！進洞得分！
Lucky shot.
運氣好啦
No more points for lucky shots.
運氣沒囉
At least I made it.
至少我進一個了
I made it again! Was that one lucky?
又進了！這樣還只是運氣好嗎？
Of course.
當然啊
That's how a real man throws it.
真男人就要這樣丟～
Don't get too excited over one shot.
不要因為中一次就太得意了你
I've made two to your one.
誒我中兩次你才一次啊
I'm still the champion, though.
不管怎樣我還是冠軍
You know what?
你知道嗎？
One day I will be a buzkashi rider.
有一天我也會變成其中一名選手的
How are you going to do that?
你要怎麼變成選手呢？
You think I'm going to be on the streets forever?
難道你覺得我永遠都會在街道上嗎？
You don't have a horse.
你又沒有馬，
You need a horse to be a buzkashi rider.
[馬背叼羊]選手都要馬啊
Don't worry, I have a plan.
別擔心，我有計劃
One day the announcer
有一天那個司儀
will call out my name in front of everyone.
在群眾面前會喊出我的名字
I'll be remembered as a buzkashi champion.
人們會記得我是一位[馬背叼羊]的冠軍
You have big dreams.
你有好多好大的夢想
I know what my future will be.
我知道我的未來會是怎麼樣的
I'm going to be a blacksmith like my father.
我會像我父親一樣成為一名鐵匠
Nothing can change that.
沒有什麼會改變這件事
You're wrong. You can do anything you want.
你錯了，只要你想做，你可以做任何事
Come on. I want to show you something.
來，我想給你看個東西
Whose palace was this?
這地方是誰的啊？
Who cares?
誰在乎阿？
I think it was some king.
我想應該是某個國王吧
Come on.
來啦
Where are we going?
我們要去哪裡？
Go ahead, climb up.
過來 我們爬上去
Go on.
往上阿
I can't.
我沒辦法
You always say that.
你總是這樣說
This is how you do it.
真男人要這樣爬
Ahmad, be careful, you'll fall.
Ahmad，小心點你會掉下來的
Look, it's easy. Don't worry so much.
你看，這很簡單，不要擔心這麼多啦
Forget it. I'm not doing it.
算了，我才不要爬呢
If you can't climb up here,
如果你連這裡都爬不到，
what kind of buzkashi rider will you be?
你能當什麼[馬背叼羊]選手呢？
You'll be a blacksmith all your life.
你一生都只能當個鐵匠
My name is Ahmad, son of Abdullah!
我的名字是Ahmad！我是Abdullah的兒子！！
And I will be a buzkashi rider!
而我將會成為一位[馬背叼羊] 選手！
I have to get back to the shop.
我要回店裡去了
My father's waiting.
我爸爸在等我
See you later.
等會見囉
Wait a minute.
等一下
What?
什麼？
Oh, wow.
哇賽！！！
Where did you get this?
你從哪裡拿到這個的？
I got it from a buzkashi rider.
一個[馬背叼羊] 選手給我的
When did you meet a buzkashi rider?
你怎麼會遇見選手的啊？
Here, wear it like this.
來，你這樣穿
This way your dad won't see it.
這樣你爸就不會看到了
If you keep it with you all the time,
如果你一直穿著它，
you'll be strong enough to ride buzkashi.
你就會變得堅強，強到你成為一位選手的。
Now go.
現在走吧。
Remember that you don't have to be a blacksmith.
記住，你並不是一定要成為一位鐵匠的。
Right.
恩...
See you tomorrow.
明天見了。
Goodbye.
再見
Where were you?
你去哪了？
You were with that fatherless beggar again, no?
你又去跟那個沒爹的小乞丐鬼混了對吧？
Listen to me.
你聽好了
I want these sharp enough to shave with.
我要這些銳利到可以削鐵
And you'll have no dinner tonight. Get started.
而你今晚將沒有晚飯吃，現在開始吧
Rafi.
It's late. Go to sleep.
很晚了，快睡吧
My grandfather was a blacksmith.
我祖父就是個鐵匠，
So was my father.
而我爸爸也是。
I was your age when I first picked up a hammer.
我在你這個年紀的時候第一次拿起鐵錘。
A blacksmith lives an honorable life.
鐵匠活出的是榮耀的一生。
Rafi.
What?
什麼？
Come on, I want to show you something.
過來，我想給你看個東西
Okay.
喔..好
Let's go.
我們走吧
So, are you a master blacksmith yet?
所以，你已經是鑄鐵大師了嗎？
All I do is sharpen axe heads.
我只負責把斧頭前端磨利而已...
You think you can swing a hammer
你覺得你瘦巴巴的手臂
with those scrawny arms?
可以揮動那些斧頭嗎？
Laugh it up.
儘管笑吧你
Where are we going?
我們到底要去哪？
Be patient. It's a surprise.
耐心點，這是驚喜
We're going up there.
我們要到上面那邊
Come on.
來吧
Hey there.
嘿！你好阿
You're a beauty.
你真是漂亮
You're a real beauty.
你真的好美
Take this.
幫我拿一下
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Stop! What are you doing?,
停下來！你在幹嘛！
Get down!
快下來！
You said I needed a horse to ride buzkashi.
你說我需要一匹馬才能當選手
Now I have one!
現在我有一匹馬了！
Praise God the great and merciful ..
願上帝的慈愛與恩惠憐憫他...
Let's go.
我們走吧。
Take the hammer.
拿好這個鎚子
We need to shape the axe head. Hit it here.
我們要讓斧頭的前端變利，鎚這裡
What kind of hammering is that, boy?
你在鎚什麼東西阿！小子
Hit it like that.
要像這樣鎚
You're not listening.
你根本沒在聽
Like this.
像這樣！
Here, you do it.
來，你做做看
What are you doing?
你到底在幹什麼？
Is that how you hammer?
這是你鎚打的方式嗎？
Son!
兒子！
Rafi!
Ahmad!
Where were you, boy?
小子，你跑哪去啦？
You said you would teach me.
你說過你會教我的，
Will you teach me now?
你現在還願意教我嗎？
Good job.
做的好
Well done.
做的非常好。